AKSHAY G

Front-End Developer | JavaScript | React | Html | Css

+91 **87 54 070533** akshayg2422@gmail.com Gummidipoondi, Chennai

SUMMARY

Persevering learner and diligent team player with 2.10 years of experience specializing in UI development using the React library. Skilled software engineer with expertise in AI-powered recruiting applications, HRMS, Budgie-CEM, Ticket management, Educational timeline systems, and ERP applications. You can view my portfolio here.

SKILLS

Javascript, Typescript, HTML, CSS, React, Bootstrap, Mui, Redux, Redux Toolkit, Redux

Saga, Redux thunk, React Router, Git, GitHub, Bit bucket, Azure, Git lab, Rest, Axios, Fetch,

Scss, Firebase, i18n-is, Iitsi, validate.js, Yup

PROJECTS

BUDGIE - CE - Lead Management

https://ce.budgie.co.in/

- Developed a lead management app for contract employees, with key modules for efficient lead handling and sales management.
- The **Lead Management** module allows users to add leads, view lead info, log activities, track follow-ups, and manage lead history with search, sorting, and filtering options, along with bulk upload functionality.
- The **Sales List** module enables searching, sorting, and filtering of sales info, adding new clients, and bulk uploading, all with scroll pagination for seamless navigation.
- The **Roles & Permissions** module provides functionality to create roles, assign them, and manage permissions.
- The **Client Onboarding** module facilitates KYC document management.
- The **Agreement Status** module tracks the approval process of agreements, with detailed status and info tracking.

Contribution: Integrated **Microsoft Login**, developed **Lead Management**, **Sales List**, **Roles & Permission**, **Client Onboarding**, **Agreement Status**, and **Location Services** modules for efficient project management, data handling, and role-based access.

Tech Stack: React, Redux-Toolkit, React Router, HTML5, CSS, Mui, Yup

SPOTLINE - Attendance

https://attendance-dev-portal.citpl.info/

• Spotline is an all-in-one attendance management app designed to streamline workforce tracking and enhance operational efficiency.

Contribution: Payroll, Search, Upload, Table List, Payslip download

Tech Stack: React, Redux-Toolkit, React Router, CSS, Mui,

PULSE

https://webportaldev.ckdigital.in/

• Pulse is a survey platform to automate the insights-gathering process and quickly find out what consumers are thinking

Contribution: Create project form with filters, Duplicate targets, Duplicate and edit projects, Completed and In completed list view, Send notification.

Tech Stack: React, Redux-Toolkit, React Router, CSS, Bootstrap,

MARKETING AUTOMATION

https://marketingautomationdev.ckdigital.in/api

Contribution: Bar chart, stacked chart, Doughnut chart, Graph chart, Crud in Table, Api integration, Hierarchy based filters

Tech Stack: React, Redux-Toolkit, React Router, CSS, Mui, Scss,

INTRVU SPACE — Hiring Application (AI)

https://www.intrvu.space/

• intrvu SPACE helps you conduct automated Interviews, Generate Reports, and Approve Candidates end to end with zero manual effort.

Contribution: Landing page, Login, OTP, Corporate flow, CRUD candidate flow, Settings, Job seeker flow, Report

Tech Stack: React, Redux, Redux Saga, React Router, HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, Validate.js

KLOCKMATE - HRMS

https://klockmate.com/

• Employee management application with features like attendance and payroll management.

Contribution: Api integration and data normalization, Salary slip.

Tech Stack: React, Redux, Redux Saga, React Router, Bootstrap, push notification

QUANTA TMS — Ticket Management Solution

• Enhances task and ticket management for improved collaboration.

Contribution: Login, OTP, Individual & Group chats, Task, Ticket, Association, Feeds, Event Tech Stack: React, Redux, Redux Saga, React Router, Bootstrap, Validate.js, push notification

QUANTA EDAT — EduTech Application

Offers comprehensive programming courses with practical tasks and mock

interviews.

Contribution: Course CRUD, Tasks, Topics, Schedule Interview, Online Sessions

Tech Stack: React, Redux, Redux Saga, React Router, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Validate.js

NS Instruments - FG — Finished Goods Management

• Optimises inventory control with streamlined stock and product management.

Contribution: Login, OTP, Dispatch request, Stock request and Paginated Listing **Tech Stack:** React, Redux, Redux Saga, React Router, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Validate.js, push notification

EXPERIENCE

React JS Developer - 06/11/2024 - Present

Cavin Infotech Private Limited - TECCI PARK, Karapakkam, Chennai.

- Responsible for frontend design, development and deployment.
- Proficient in developing UI for web applications primarily on React JS
- Skilled in developing modular components to ensure scalability and maintainability
- Collaborate effectively with UI/UX designers to implement designs that enhance user experience
- Proactively troubleshoot and debug issues to ensure smooth functioning of applications
- Stay updated with the latest technologies through continuous research and self-learning
- Oversee testing protocols to maintain the quality and reliability of applications

React JS Developer - 17/06/2024 - 31/10/2024

SightSpectrumTechnology Solutions (P) Ltd. - Tidel, Tiruvanmyur.

CLIENT - Cavin Infotech Private Limited

- Responsible for frontend design, development and deployment.
- Proficient in developing UI for web applications primarily on React JS
- Skilled in developing modular components to ensure scalability and maintainability
- Collaborate effectively with UI/UX designers to implement designs that enhance user experience
- Proactively troubleshoot and debug issues to ensure smooth functioning of applications
- Stay updated with the latest technologies through continuous research and self-learning
- Oversee testing protocols to maintain the quality and reliability of applications

React JS Developer - 06/2022 - 15/06/2024

Leora Infotech Private Limited - Gummidipoondi, Chennai.

- Responsible for frontend design and development
- Proficient in developing UI for web applications primarily on React JS
- Skilled in developing modular components to ensure scalability and maintainability
- Collaborate effectively with UI/UX designers to implement designs that enhance user experience
- Proactively troubleshoot and debug issues to ensure smooth functioning of applications
- Stay updated with the latest technologies through continuous research and self-learning
- Oversee testing protocols to maintain the quality and reliability of applications

Tele Marketing Assistant - 17/03/2022 - 31/05/2022

Malayala Manorama Company Limited - Egmore, Chennai.

Payment Assistance - 30/09/2021 - 14/03/2022

MATRIMONY.COM LIMITED - Guindy, Chennai.

- As a Payment Assistant, I facilitated payments and supported users navigating the payment page.
- Utilizing chat and system calls, I addressed user concerns, convinced them of package benefits, and ensured a smooth transaction experience.

Data Provisioning Executive - 01/2019 - 11/2019

Tenth Planet Technologies - Mount Road, Chennai.

• Provide customized enterprise IT solutions, centered around open source software, troubleshoot issues, and ensure compliance.

Process Associate - 04/2017 - 11/2017

String Information Services - Saidapet, Chennai.

• Mortgage Process Outsourcing (MPO) - tailored solutions, optimize and streamline mortgage processes, enhance efficiency, reduce costs.

EDUCATION

Bsc Computer Science - 2013 - 2016

Shree Chandraprabhu Jain College Minjur, Chennai.

XII (HSS) - 2011 -2013

St. Marys Matric Hr Sec Chinthala Kuppam, Gummidipoondi.

X (SSLC) - 2010 - 2011

Shanthiniketan Matric Hr Sec New Gummidipoondi.

LANGUAGES

Tamil: Mother Tongue English: Professional (Conversationally fluent)

Malayalam: Conversationally fluent Hindi: Writing and Reading